JD PIRTLE | RESUME

1523 N. Cleveland Ave. #4S Chicago, IL 60610 t| 312-508-0561 e| jdpirtle@gmail.com w| jdpirtle.com

PROFILE

Artist and technologist highly skilled in the design and creation of algorithmic, interactive applications and artworks. Passionate investigator, developer and user of emerging technologies. Researcher in a world-renowned advanced visualization laboratory. Extremely comfortable in the command line.

EDUCATION

MFA | New Media Arts/Electronic Visualization, 2009-2011

University of Illinois at Chicago | adweb.aa.uic.edu

BFA | Digital Art and Experimental Media with Departmental Honors, 2005-2008

Center for Digital Arts and Experimental Media (DXARTS), University of Washington | dxarts.washington.edu

RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Artist and Researcher | Electronic Visualization Laboratory, 2011-Present

University of Illinois at Chicago | evl.uic.edu

Role: Artist and Researcher in advanced visualization and multichannel audio in an interdisciplinary laboratory that unites computer science, art, electrical engineering, biology, and communications

- Collaborating on design, implementation and construction of CAVE2 Virtual Reality Environment, a 72 display/36 node immersive virtual reality environment
- Design and implementation of 22-channel audio system
- Authored software for creating ambisonic multichannel audio
- Development of interactive software applications for large multitouch tiled displays

Research Assistant | Electronic Visualization Laboratory, 2010-2011

University of Illinois at Chicago

Role: Graduate research assistant

- Designed and developed websites and databases
- · Collaborated on interactive multitouch applications on large scale, high-resolution display walls
- Designed and implemented multichannel audio systems and software

Teaching Assistant | Advanced Electronic Visualization and Critique, 2010

Electronic Visualization Graduate Seminar, University of Illinois at Chicago

Role: Teaching assistant for graduate level course that culminated in solo exhibitions on the The Jackman Goldwasser Catwalk Gallery at the Hyde Park Arts Center

- Assisted graduate students in the creation of large, interactive artworks designed for a 70 foot projected façade
- Configured software for controlling the cluster of computers driving the projected facade

IT/Creative Technologist | Teams Design Chicago, 2009-2010

Chicago, IL | teamsdesign.com/usa/

Role: IT and creative technologist in large industrial design firm

- Provided creative technical support to designers working with Rhino and Solidworks
- Designed and implemented interactive applications, including a large multitouch conference room wall
- System administrator of network and storage servers

Visiting Artist and Instructor | DXARTS, 2009

Center for Digital Arts and Experimental Media (DXARTS), University of Washington | dxarts.washington.edu Role: Instructor of record of 3 Space: Special Topics in 3D Computer Arts

Taught undergraduate course that focused on the creation of holograms with Autodesk Maya

Research Assistant | DXARTS, 2008-2009

Center for Digital Arts and Experimental Media (DXARTS) University of Washington | dxarts.washington.edu

Role: Research assistant to Shawn Brixey, director of DXARTS

- Translated historical experimental artworks to 3d animations for archival purposes
- Modeling, lighting, animation in Autodesk Maya
- Technical photography

IT/Technology Studies Instructor, 2007-2008

Seattle Public Schools | seattleschools.org

Role: IT and instructor for Seattle Public Schools

- Provided IT support to staff, students and instructors
- · Designed and taught a technology studies course, with an emphasis on creative digital output
- System administrator of network and storage servers

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

Proficient: Processing, Processing.js, Supercollider, Arduino, HTML, CSS, JQuery Experience with: Javascript, openFrameworks, Java, Max/MSP, Python, Rhino, MYSQL, PHP

Learning: C, Scala

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY:

Git, Autodesk Maya, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Final Cut Pro, Audacity (and a variety of other DAWs), MrMr, TouchOSC, MeshLab

RELAVENT SKILLS

3D Modeling, Animation and Rendering

- Seven years of experience modeling, animating, and rendering in Autodesk Maya
- Maya generalist, but with a focus on particle, fluid, and smoke simulations

Stereoscopic 3D

- Seven years of experience producing stereoscopic 3D animation and video
- Production of a variety of stereo 3D formats (passive polarized, interleaved, anaglyphic and active shutter)
- Stereo 3D animation pipeline using Autodesk Maya and Adobe After Effects
- Stereo 3D video pipeline with experience using a variety of Stereo 3D HD cameras and rigs, post-production in Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere and Final Cut Pro

Arduino and Electronics

- Sensing and control systems using various models of the Arduino electronic prototyping platform and IDE
- Networked and interactive artworks with a variety of sensors, motors, and input devices
- Building complex circuits

Computer Vision

• Interactive applications and artworks using a variety of computer vision technologies, ranging in complexity from modified webcams to IR cameras to Microsoft Kinect

Rapid Prototyping

• Production of artworks through 3D printing, CNC routing, and laser cutting/etching

Algorithmic/Real-time and Traditional Audio

- 15 years of experience composing, performing, recording and producing traditional audio
- Programming real-time audio applications and artworks using Supercollider and Max/MSP

Web Development

- Eight years of experience in web development with proficiency in HTML/CSS/JQuery
- Experience with JavaScript, PHP and MySQL

Video Production

• Eight years of experience in traditional (2D) video production/post-production, including lighting, compositing, and chroma keying